Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we're looking for a new job.
That's right we are looking for a new job
and so we're bringing you this great lesson
where we're going to teach you
in English a lot of terms related
with looking for a job or
things like a resume, cover letter.
So before we get on into
that why don't we take
a look at a word that we
have in vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
So this is actually the name of a job,
it's a position to gas station attendant.
Okay a gas station attendant.
Now we know what a gas station is, right?
That's right, it's a place where
you go to fill your car with gas.
Okay, so in attendance add a
gas station, what does he do?
He or she as a person who will
help you put the gas in your car.
So an attendant is someone who is
almost like an assistant or a helper.
Okay.
You can have a bathroom
attendant, someone who
gives you a towel after
you wash your hand.
I've seen those in the fancy restaurants.
Yeah, so gas station attendant.
All right.
So why don't we
take a look now at our
dialogue, let's listen to it for the
first time and we'll be back in a bit.
Woo-hoo, this just might be
the start of the rest of my life.
What happened? I'm in the market for a job.
I went on a website
with hundreds of job
listings in the area and
browsed through them
until I got the names of a few
employers I would like to work for.
I have the resume I
wrote for English class
last month and a cover letter
will be a piece of cake to write.
I've even done my research
and found the names
of the managers so I
can address the letters
personally and you know I
can be charming and interviews.
Goodbye my penniless
days, hello salary and a career.
Ben, we're 15.
What kind of job are you looking for?
Oh, just for a position
as a gas station
attendant, you know
starting at a simple, lowly
job just like all the greats before
they made it big in the world.
Uh-huh.
But I'm just in it for the money, right?
How else am I going to be able to
afford to keep taking Angela to the movies?
Besides, I love the smell
of gasoline, don't you?
All right, we're back so now you're
probably wondering what those words meant.
So why don't we take a look at a
couple of them in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
The first phrase we
have today is one that's
very important when
you're looking for a job.
It's called job listing
or job listings here.
Okay, job listings.
This is really common
before the internet
existed, you would have the
listings in your local newspaper, right?
Exactly.
And in the movies, you
always had the person
sitting with the newspaper
circling the potential jobs.
Right.
With the red markers.
Exactly.
But now that we have the internet, you have
lots of websites that have job listings.
And so a job listing is literally
a list of jobs that are available.
Okay.
So you look through the job listings.
Maybe you found one that's interesting.
There's an email address.
So what do they ask for?
They ask you to send in your resume.
Okay.
Resume is very important
when you're looking for a job.
It's a document, it's a piece
of paper that tells someone all
of the work that you've done
before, your job experiences.
And it tells them where you went to
school and what your qualifications are.
So it's a summary of your work life.
Okay.
And that's why it's called a resume, right?
It's pretty much a summary
of your work life, as you say.
That's right.
And a different one,
sometimes people use
this as a CV, curriculum, VTA, and
that's an academic summary of your life.
So you have the work
summary and the study summary.
Okay.
Very good.
So if you send in your resume, what's
recommended is that you attach it with a cover
letter.
Okay.
Well, cover letter.
You know the word letter.
It's something that you
write to somebody else.
But a cover letter is like
a cover for your resume.
It's a letter where you
explain to the future
boss or future employer
what exactly you
want and how this job is
going to help you get it.
Okay.
So that's basically a small little
introduction to yourself, right?
Before they read your
resume, who you are,
what you're looking
for, maybe very quickly.
Exactly.
So you can say hi, my name is Catherine.
I'm very motivated
and excited to have the
opportunity to talk to
you about why I'm a skilled
employee and why I will
benefit your company.
Very good.
All right.
So you've sent in your
resume and your cover letter.
And well, maybe you're looking to get
into a career as a gas station attendant.
Hmm.
So what's the difference
between job and career?
Okay.
And this is very
interesting because in many
languages, there is a similar word, which
for example, in Spanish is Carrera, right?
And that means like a profession.
So many people translate it literally
as career, but it's not the right word.
What is a career?
A career, I think of as a long term
goal, a career is your profession.
It's the name you give
yourself, but a job is a,
a position in a company
from one time to another.
So for example, my job
here is host of English
pot, but maybe in the future,
I will have a media career.
That means that my, my job or jobs
will have to do with this profession.
It's kind of a bigger
thing, a longer thing.
So maybe you can think of it this way.
A career is like, as you say, a bigger
picture, like the macro category, right?
You're into media and
television, for example.
And your job specifically
is a podcast host.
But in the future, maybe
I want to have a different
job in this career and move into
production and be a TV producer.
So that's a part of my career path.
I can move forward.
So career is very important word.
All right.
So we've taken a look at
a couple of great words.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue
again and we'll be back in a bit.
Woo hoo.
This just might be the
start of the rest of my life.
What happened?
I'm in the market for a job.
I went on a website with
hundreds of job listings
in the area and browse
through them until
I got the names of a few
employers I would like to work for.
I have the resume I
wrote for English class
last month and a cover letter
will be a piece of cake to write.
I've even done my research
and found the names
of the managers so I can
address the letters personally.
And you know, I can be
charming and interviews.
Goodbye my penniless
days, hello salary and a career.
Ben, we're 15.
What kind of job are you looking for?
Oh, just for a position as a gas station
attendant, you know, starting at a simple,
lowly job just like all the greats
before they made it big in the world.
Uh-huh.
But I'm just in it for the money, right?
How else am I going to be able to
afford to keep taking Angela to the movies?
Besides, I love the smell
of gasoline, don't you?
All right, we're back so
now we have lined up for
you three key phrases that
we found in this dialogue.
So let's take a look at those
now, influence you builder.
Fluency Builder.
This first one's a great phrase.
It's going to make you sound
very fluent in English if you use it.
We say in the market for.
I'm in the market for a new job.
All right, so this person
is looking for a new job.
He is in the market for.
I could also say I'm in the
market for a new house.
Mark, do you know any
good real estate agents?
So what does that
mean if you say I'm in the
market for a new job or you're
in the market for a new house?
I am right now actively
looking for this thing.
I really want one.
You're available.
Yes.
OK.
So I'm in the market for a new job.
I'm in the market for a new car.
I mean, the market is the marketplace.
Right, right.
And this sometimes you could
see it related in movies, for example.
They say if a person gets married,
they are no longer in the market.
Right.
Or I'm in the market for a husband.
Do you know what a nice guy is?
All right.
So you're in the market.
You're looking for a job.
And well, if you're qualified, it will
be a piece of cake to find a new job.
Mmm.
Isn't this a delicious phrase?
So piece of cake, you think, what
does cake have to do with anything?
Well, cake, this is a way
to say something is easy.
OK.
So it's really easy.
This often happens in our office, actually,
because you and I understand computers.
But we work with someone who
has a hard time with computers.
Right.
And she says, oh, it doesn't work.
And we're like, it's a piece of cake.
It's a piece of cake.
It's so easy.
Why is this hard?
So a piece of cake is a way
to say something simple.
And it's a very, very, very common phrase.
You'll hear it all the time.
A piece of cake, don't worry about it.
Piece of cake.
Hey, can you help me out with this thing?
Sure, it's a piece of cake.
All right.
And for our last phrase, he was talking
about his position as a gas attendant.
And he said, well, you know, all
the grades, all the famous people,
they started somewhere
before they made it big.
What does he mean with, they made it big?
Well, the phrase, to make
it big, or in here in the
past tense, made it big,
means to be successful.
So we're talking about,
for example, Albert Einstein.
Albert Einstein worked in the patent
office in a, he was a clerk in Europe.
And, you know, that's not a very
impressive job, but it was a job.
And he made it big later on as a physicist.
And so to make it big is to succeed, to
become famous or successful or important.
Right.
Or sometimes people say, yeah, I made it.
I made it big or I made it in my life.
And that means that you were successful.
Or this product is going to make it big.
It's going to be really successful.
Yeah, that's good.
OK, so it's a key phrase
to make it or to make it big.
Why don't we listen
to our dialogue for the
last time and we'll
be back in a little bit.
Woo-hoo!
This just might be the
start of the rest of my life.
What happened?
I'm in the market for a job.
I went on a website
with hundreds of job
listings in the area and
browse through them
until I got the names of a few
employers I would like to work for.
I have the resume I
wrote for English class
last month and a cover letter
will be a piece of cake to write.
I've even done my research
and found the names
of the managers so I
can address the letters
personally and you know I
can be charming and interviews.
Goodbye my penniless
days, hello salary and a career.
Ben, we're 15.
What kind of job are you looking for?
Oh, just for a position as a gas station
attendant, you know, starting at a simple,
lowly job just like all the greats
before they made it big in the world.
Uh-huh.
But I'm just in it for the money, right?
How else am I going to be able to
afford to keep taking Angela to the movies?
Besides, I love the smell
of gasoline, don't you?
Alright, so talking
about jobs, now I noticed
something that in the
United States, unlike
many other countries, there are
no gas station attendants anymore.
There are.
Uh, to say, there, there
are actually a lot of
gas station attendants
in New Jersey because
it's the law that you cannot pump your
own gas, you cannot be gas in your own car.
Why is that?
It's a, a way for the
New Jersey government
to increase the amount
of jobs in the States.
So to create jobs, they
made gas station attendants.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, I've noticed
in some States, for
example, you just go up
to the pump and if you
have your credit card, you put in your
credit card and you pump your own gas.
And apparently it also
has to do with health
issues because people
who are working at
in gas stations, uh, tend to have
serious health problems later on.
I mean, you're inhaling all these,
uh, gases from, from the gasoline.
That's right.
It's very unhealthy and I think that's also
very dangerous in some places because gas
stations are often robbed because there's
only one person and no security sometimes.
So, uh, there are some negative
parts of being a gas station attendant.
But if it's a job and you need a job, it's
probably, uh, it's probably a good one.
Yeah.
No, true.
I actually, I remember seeing back to the
future when, uh, in the 50s, you would pull
up to a gas station and somebody
would check your tire pressure.
They would check your
oil and they would clean
your windows and it's just like full
service when you pulled up to a gas station.
They might even buy you a beer.
No.
All right.
So, um, it's really interesting
about these positions.
I imagine that, you
know, in other places,
some job positions and maybe we, we would
find a little bit strange or uncommon.
Absolutely.
And I encourage everyone today.
This is your homework.
Tell us on EnglishPod.com.
What is your job and what's your career?
Okay.
What's your job and what's your career?
So what's the career you
would like to have in the future?
Very good.
All right.
So we'll see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.